# Nana Araba Essien-Baidoo (Mrs).

MARITAL STATUS: Married RELIGION: Christian

#### BIO

Having worked as a teacher with the Ghana Education Service for all these years, I have acquired enormous knowledge and expertise in teaching, administration including leadership in curriculum and school based health coordination.

I also have a worth of knowledge in child care and social work involving advocacy for vulnerable children and persons living with disabilities. My focus is to bring to bear these in any institution bearing in mind contextualized issues in global education and school management.

#### **SKILLS**

- 1. Multi-disciplinary, reliable team player.
- 2. Able to create a workable schedule to meet deadlines efficiently.
- 3. Major strengths in planning, problem solving and communication.
- 4. Computer literate.

#### **EDUCATION**

# 2016 – 2019 MPhil, Administration in Higher Education

University of Cape Coast,

Cape Coast, Ghana.

# 2013-2015 B. Ed. Mathematics

University of Cape Coast, Cape Coast, Ghana.

# Dip. Management Studies

2011-2013 University of Cape Coast,

Cape Coast, Ghana.

2004-2007 Dip. In Basic Education

St. Louis College of Education,

Kumasi, Ghana.

2000 - 2003 S.S.S.C.E Business

Fijai Secondary School Sekondi –W/R, Ghana

## **EXPERIENCE**

Sep. 2017 – Date Curriculum Leader

E.J.P. Brown Methodist Primary School

Cape Coast

Sep. 2016 - Date School based Health Coordinator

E.J.P. Brown Methodist Primary School

Cape Coast

2010 - Date Teacher

E.J.P. Brown Methodist Primary School

Cape Coast

2007 - 2010 Girl Child Coordinator

**Apomase Methodist Primary School** 

Kumasi, Ghana

2005 - 2006 S.R.C President

St. Louis College of Education

Kumasi, Ghana.

#### RESEARCH INTEREST AND AREAS

- 1. Effectiveness of the Committee System in the Management of Colleges of Education in the Central Region of Ghana.
- 2. Use of flashcards to improve pronunciation of Fante words.

# SCHOLARSHIPS/GRANTS/AWARDS

1. Samuel and Emelia Brew-Butler- SGS/ GRASAG Research Grant

#### PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS AND SOCIETIES

Member, Ghana National Association of Teachers

#### WORKSHOP/CONFERENCES ATTENDED

### Standard Based Curriculum

Organized by: Ghana Education Service

Date: August, 2019

Venue: Amanful Catholic Boys JHS, Cape Coast

## 2. Training on Girls Iron And Folate Tablets Supplementation ( GIFTS)

Organized by: Ghana Health Service and Ghana Education Service

Date: May, 2019

Venue: University Hospital Conference Room, UCC- Cape Coast

# 3. Early Grade Reading

Organized by: USAID Partnership for Education

Date: August, 2017

Venue: Philip Quaque Girls' Primary School

# 4. UDL: A Pedagogical tool for today's Diverse and Inclusive Classroom

Organized by: University of Education, Winneba

Date: March, 2018

Venue: Conference Room, Cape Coast School for the Deaf

## 5. Handwashing and Brushing of Teeth

Organized by: Unilever Ghana

Date: March, 2017

Venue: Cape Coast Teaching Hospital

Role: Facilitator

## 6. Malaria Vector Control Programme

Organized by: G.E.S and G.H.S

Date: February, 2017

Venue: St. Monica's Anglican Girls' Primary

## **REFERENCES**

Name: Prof. Yaw A. Ankomah

Address: Institute for Educational Planning and Administration, UCC, Cape Coast.

Tel: 0244070280

Email: yankomah@ucc.edu.gh

Name: Dr. Michael Boakye-Yiadom

Address: Institute for Educational Planning and Administration, UCC, Cape Coast.

Tel: 0261171143

Email: mboakye-yiadom@ucc.edu.gh